（火ノ丸(ひのまる)）ウヘヘッ…
Demon Wheel!
（千比路(ちひろ)）鬼車(おにぐるま)！
（荒木(あらき)）ウワッ！
The strongest!
（千比路）最強ーっ！
Using a sumo technique at that moment...
（柴木山(しばきやま)）ここに来て 相撲技
That was Hinomaru's Demon Wheel!
（寺原(てらはら)）火ノ丸の鬼車！
Yes!
（礼奈(れいな)）やった〜！
（西郷）決まった！
He did it!
Dachi High wins the second bout!
（舟木）
二陣戦は ダチ高の勝ちだ！
That was judo versus wrestling.
柔道対レスリング
レスリングに軍配ってことですか？
Does this mean wrestling has the upper hand?
No, it doesn't.
いや 違う　これは
異種格闘技戦なんかじゃなかった
This wasn't a battle between
two different combat sports.
もし ２人が柔道で戦えば
強いのは荒木だ
If this had been a judo bout,
Araki would've come out on top.
And conversely, Kunisaki would've had
the upper hand in a wrestling match.
逆に
レスリングなら 國崎(くにさき)のほうが強い
But this is sumo.
（寺原）でも これは相撲
We may have just heard Kunisaki-kun's
first cry as a newborn sumo wrestler.
（柴木山）
もしかして僕らは 今日—
國崎君の力士としての産声を
聞いたのかもしれない
Bout 8
"What's Done is Done"
Yo, Hotaru!
（千比路）よう ホタル
I made up for your loss,
and now we're tied.
お前(めえ)の負けを
チャラにしてやったぜ
Thank you very much!
（蛍(けい)）
ありがとうございます！
Ow!
いってえ！　あれ　ちょ…
Dude, were you always this strong?
His skill is terrifying.
（桐仁(きりひと)）
末恐ろしいっつうか何つうか…
Yeah.
I've done my bit, Captain.
きっちり仕事したぜ　大将
Thanks to me, we can afford one more loss.
俺のおかげで
あと１敗までならできるぜ
（佑真(ゆうま)）
な… 何が言いてえんだ？　てめえ
What are you trying to say?
Just thought taking on a stronger opponent
might have you quaking in your boots.
格上の相手に
ビビっちゃってんのかと思ってよ
（佑真）
ビビる？　誰に言ってやがる
Quaking?
Who do you think you're talking to?
After that display you guys just put on,
お前らの
あんな戦い見せられて—
俺だけ カッコ悪いところ
見せられねえだろう
I've got no intention of letting anyone down.
Winning's the only thought in my mind.
勝つこと以外 考えてねえよ
Third bout. On the west side, Gojo-kun.
（アナウンス）中堅戦…
（男性１）うん？　何だ？　あいつ
What's he doing?
On the east side, Kanamori-kun.
He lost, but he isn't getting out of the ring.
（男性２）
負けたのに土俵を下りねえぞ
Hey, kid...
（審判）おい　君
Hey!
（金盛(かなもり)）おい！
（荒木）あっ…
Your strength lies in
not overthinking things.
（金盛）ゴチャゴチャ考えねえのが
お前の長所だろうが
It's our job now to make up for it.
（金盛）
責任を取るのは俺たちの仕事だ
You'll have to do the same someday.
ただ
お前にも その役目は回ってくる
Watch us closely so you'll know
what to do when the time comes.
（金盛）そのいつかのためにも
今は 俺らの姿をよく見ておけ
Yuma isn't gonna lose, right?
（礼奈）佑真 負けないよね？
The guy he's facing looks pretty strong.
なんか強そうなヤツが
相手だけど—
But Yuma's won all of his bouts today!
佑真だって
ここまで 全勝で来てんだもん
Kanamori-kun, on the west side, wins!
（アナウンス）西 金盛君の勝ち！
He isn't Ishigami's captain for nothing.
さすが石神(いしがみ)の主将　いい相撲を取る
He's got skills.
Kirihito, what are we gonna do
if we have to face him?
桐仁
あいつと戦うとしたら どうする？
From the marks on his face, it looks
like he's the type to charge in headfirst.
（桐仁）あの傷を見るに
頭からガンガン来るタイプだろう
さっきも初めから
体で ぶつかりに行った
That's what he did in the bout just now.
If he gets close to you,
there's no stopping him.
組まれたら
向こうのペースに持っていかれるぞ
We have one win and one loss.
（佑真）ここまで １勝１敗
勝負は振り出しに戻った
It's now a best-of-three.
I'll hit him on the chin as soon as we charge.
立ち合い初っぱなから 相手の顎に
俺の追い突きをたたき込む
Hands on the ground.
Even if he's stronger and
has trained more than me,
いかに鍛えた力士でも
格上でも—
he won't be able to take a whack to the chin.
顎にもらえば
ただじゃ済まねえはずだ
I can't just leave it up to
the other two to win this for us.
あとの２人に勝敗を委ねるなんて
そんな だせえマネできるかよ
何のために ここまで来たんだ
ここで勝たなきゃ—
Why have I come this far?
If I don't win here...
（佑真）男じゃねえ！
（審判）はっきよい！
I'm not a man!
Spirit!
Instead of grabbing him...
（３人）組まずに…
...he hit him!
（一同）突っ張った！
That was Captain Kanamori's Cannon Slap!
（間宮(まみや)）
出た！　金盛主将の“大砲(おおづつ)”！
Gojo Yuma...
（金盛）五條(ごじょう)佑真　知ってるぜ
ダチ高の番格なんだってな
I know who you are.
You're the leader of the Dachi High gang.
Ishi High is the nexus of
delinquents in this prefecture,
石高は 県内でも
屈指の不良の巣窟だから—
so we hear all about what goes on
in other schools even if we don't care.
そういう情報は
イヤでも耳に入ってくる
Ishigami
Private
High
School
Asshole
More Like
Primate
Come to think of it, our club has a long
history of scuffling with delinquents.
思えば 石高相撲部の歴史は
不良どもとの戦いの歴史でもあった
They used to harass us, time and again.
何度も嫌がらせを受けてきたし—
We've even been barred from competing
'cause of trouble they'd created.
ヤツらが外で起こした問題のせいで
出場停止になったこともある
They're an unpleasant bunch, for sure.
（金盛）本当に不愉快な連中だよ
なあ 真田(さなだ)
Isn't that right, Sanada?
You punks will stop getting in our way!
お前ら これ以上
俺たちのジャマをするな！
Yuma!
（礼奈）佑真！
（西郷）マズイ！　もう土俵際だ！
Oh, no! He's been pushed back to the edge!
（佑真）負けるのか？
このまま なすすべもなく
Am I gonna lose?
Be helplessly destroyed?
"My opponent's stronger than me"?
相手は格上　しかたない？
"Nothing I can do"?
But I knew that when I stepped into the ring.
分かってたことだろう そんなのは
What am I doing here?
俺は何しに ここへ来た？
何のために？
Why am I here in this ring?
No. You are no longer my student.
（高荷(たかに)）断る
お前は もう私の生徒じゃないし
チンピラに教えることは何もない
I have nothing to teach a thug like you.
Karate Shinshinkan
W-Wait, Takani-chan!
（佑真）
ちょ…　待ってくれ 高荷師範
At least hear me out!
話だけでも聞いてくれ！
Take one more step, and I call the police.
そこ またいだら 警察呼ぶよ
The p-police?
け… 警察？
Go on. I'm listening.
（高荷）話なら聞いてる
相撲部に入ったんだってね
I heard you'd joined a sumo club.
A polite young man with thick, long hair
（高荷）メガネのモサモサした子が
ご丁寧に菓子折持って 頼みに来た
brought me some baked sweets
and made a request.
So? Are you just going to let
a younger kid ask for you?
（高荷）それで？　あんたは
後輩に頭下げさせて終わり？
Please. Let me practice karate
under your tutelage again.
お願いします
俺に また 空手を教えてください
I know I've wasted valuable years of my life.
確かに俺は 今まで
ろくでもねえ生き方をしてきた
I realized that after I picked up sumo.
それを 相撲を始めて痛感したんだ
I'm begging you. Let me train here again!
頼む　もう一度だけ
俺に稽古をつけてくれ！
Thing is, those stories about
delinquents "seeing the light"
（高荷）私はね そういう
ヤンキーの更生物語とか—
absolutely disgust me!
大っ嫌いなんだよ！
Some punk-ass kid goes around,
causing trouble for a whole load of people,
（高荷）さんざん
人さまに迷惑かけてきておいて—
and then they do one decent thing,
and everyone showers them with praise?
ちょっと人並みのことすりゃ
やたら褒められる
What a load of bullcrap.
ふざけんな
People who've always done the decent
thing are way more worthy of praise.
人並みのことを
ずっと真面目にやってるヤツが—
いちばん立派なんだ
"What's done is done."
“覆水 盆に返らず”
反省しようが しまいが—
Whether you regret what you did or not,
nothing can change the fact that you used
the karate I taught you to hurt people.
私の教えた空手で
人を泣かせた事実は消えないんだよ
Get lost.
帰れ　ほかの生徒のジャマだ！
You're distracting my students.
Dammit. I don't have time for this.
（佑真）くそ…
俺には
こんなことをしてる暇はねえ
Huh? What was that?
（高荷）ああ？　何だって？
Please!
頼む！　マジで時間がねえんだ！
I'm out of time! I mean it!
For Ozeki and the rest
of my team, I have to win!
小関(おぜき)のために みんなのためにも
俺は勝たなきゃいけねえ
I stood in his way for years and deprived
him of opportunities he could've had.
俺のせいで奪われた
あいつの時間や可能性…
I know I can never give him those back.
どうやったって返せないのは
分かってる
But I need to do what I can now.
それでも ほんの少しでもいい
俺の勝利で返してやりてえんだ！
I want to win to atone for what I did!
Why come here?
どうしてウチなの？
You could've gone to any other dojo
and spared yourself this display.
ほかの空手道場に行けば
こんなことまでしなくて済むのに
楽なほうには
逃げたくねえんだ もう
I don't want to take the
easy way out anymore.
Yuma.
（高荷）佑真
I share some of the blame.
私にも負い目は あるんだ
As your instructor, I failed to
channel your talent properly.
才能のあるお前を 指導者として
正しく導いてやれなかった
Put on your uniform.
道着に着替えな
I'll teach you special karate techniques
that will help you in sumo.
教えてやるよ　相撲にも使えそうな
とっておきの空手技を
（佑真）
ンンッ…　空手に先手なし！
In karate, you never attack first!
Karate offensive move: Twist and press!
（佑真）空手 攻法 巻き伏せ！
He pulled him forward!
（寺原）いなした！
（柴木山）うまい！
Well done!
Wait, that's a karate flip-and-switch.
いや　これは
空手でいうところの“さばき”
I knew a hastily learned karate technique
wouldn't be enough to make you fall.
（佑真）
てめえが にわか仕込みのさばきで
落ちるだなんて思ってねえさ
The real attack...
本命は…
Go!
いけー！
...is this!
こっちだ！
追い突き･開手(かいしゅ)！
Open hand lunge punch!
He...
こいつ 額で…
He blocked it with his forehead!
In an instant...
１発で 形勢が…
...the tables have turned!
（小関）ひっくり返された！
Don't underestimate a sumo wrestler,
Mr. Karate.
（真田）
相撲取りナメんなよ 空手家
The flip-and-switch won't work here.
さばきもダメ　追い突きも防がれた
He blocked my lunge punch, too.
All I have left is...
残るは…
This technique's powerful when it lands,
but the chances of pulling it off are slim.
（高荷）この技は 決まれば
威力は絶大だが 成功率は低い
What matters is your resolve.
だが 大事なのは気持ち　心だよ
Your heart.
Remember why you're here.
思い出せ　何のために
ここまで やってきたのかを
Yuma-san!
佑真さん！
（佑真）ンッ…　ハアッ！
He kicked him!
（男性１）蹴返(けかえ)し！
（男性２）…というより下段蹴りだ
More like a leg sweep!
The captain's leg won't budge an inch
from a leg sweep that desperate.
そんな苦し紛れの足払いで
主将の足が揺らぐかよ
No...
いや…
（金盛）
足を払うのが目的じゃない！？
He wasn't trying to move
my leg with that kick?
（佑真）
俺には 果たすべき責任が残ってる
I still have a job to do.
And that job is...
それは…
He accelerated.
加速した！
...to make this sumo club
what you want it to be:
（佑真）
相撲部を お前の望む所に…
The best in Japan!
日本一に 連れていくことだ！
Fortress Break Palm!
破城掌(はじょうしょう)！
Fortress
Break
Palm
Fortress
Break
Palm
It landed!
（佑真）手応えありだ！
Captain!
主将！
It's working!
効いてる！
Hit him again!
もう１発だ！
Go!
いけー！
I was too slow to react!
反応が遅れた？
I hate to admit it, but you're better
at thrusting strikes than me.
悔しいが 突き合いでの勝負は
お前のほうが上だったということか
（佑真）ンン〜ッ…
（金盛）だが…
But...
I won't let you get a win
in this team battle!
（金盛）
団体戦での勝ち星は譲らん！
Three years of high school sumo
have led up to this.
（金盛）高校相撲３年間の集大成
最後のインターハイ
My last Inter High!
This year's Ishi High team has the power to fight on a par with the national treasures!
国宝を擁する列強と
渡り合えるだけの力が—
今の石高にはある！
The strongest Ishi High sumo team in history
will become the best in Japan!
この歴代最強の石高相撲部を
日本一にする
That is my final dream.
それが 俺の最後の夢
And my final duty as their captain!
そして 主将としての最後の責務！
（金盛）ウオーッ！
（佑真）ウワッ…
Back
ward
Belt
Back
Th
ward
Backward Belt Throw!
Th
row
Belt
Th
row
Dammit!
くそ！
He threw Yuma-san with one arm.
（橋）佑真さんが片腕で…
（礼奈）そんな…
No...
As you are now, I don't think I'd lose to you
even if we contested a hundred bouts.
（金盛）今のお前には
100回やろうが 負ける気がしねえ
But that last strike of yours
was undeniably strong.
…が 最後の突き 侮れんな
Now, they have one win and two losses.
（寺原）これで １勝２敗か
Dachi High's got their backs to the wall.
（柴木山）
ダチ高は もう あとがないぞ
Bow, east!
（審判）礼 東！
Nice fight.
（小関）ナイスファイト
I-I'm sorry—
（佑真）す… すまねえ
（小関）大丈夫
Don't worry.
I'll win and set the stage for Ushio!
俺が勝って 潮(うしお)につなげます
Don't go acting all tough.
This is your first time, isn't it?
（真田）
強がるなよ　お前は初めてだろう？
Your first time in a bout where a loss
for you will spell defeat for your team.
自分の敗北が
チームを敗北させる一戦
You're trying to hide it,
but I can see it in your stomps.
必死に隠しちゃいるが
しこを見りゃ分かる
You're overwhelmed.
のまれてるぜ
I have to win. Otherwise, everyone's
hard work will be for nothing.
（小関）勝たなきゃ
みんなの頑張りを
ムダにしちゃいけない
Don't show weakness.
弱気を見せるな
負けた２人が責任を感じるだろう？
The two who lost will blame themselves.
I have to be useful to them!
ここで みんなの役に立てなくて
どうする！
俺が… 部長の俺が 勝たないと…
（鼓動音）
I... I'm the captain!
I have to win!
あっ…　俺 また小さくなってた？
I'd gotten timid again.
You're too nice, captain.
部長は優しいからのぅ
（小関）ハハハッ…　それって
つまり 頼りないってことだろう？
Is that a roundabout way
of saying I'm unreliable?
Well, you're not as reliable
as Ishi High's captain, sure.
（火ノ丸）
そりゃ 石高の主将と比べたら—
部長は だいぶ頼りないが
But what you do have
（火ノ丸）じゃが 部長には…
（小関）うん？
is a team made up of your former nemesis,
a complete novice, and an upstart.
（火ノ丸）かつての敵にも
ド新人にも 生意気な後輩にも—
And you have the compassion
to accept them all as they are.
誰にでも分け隔てなく
寄り添ってくれる優しさがある
We all agree that the only captain
our sumo club can have
みんな 思っとるよ
ダチ高相撲部の部長が務まるのは
小関信也(しんや)しかいねえってな
is Ozeki Shinya.
You've been through more than any of us,
誰より苦労して
頑張ってきた部長が—
and we want to see you beat the Ishi High.
あの強豪 石神高校に勝つところが
みんな 何より見たいんじゃ
We want to see it more than anything.
To see you emerge triumphant and
have your hard work be rewarded.
勝って その努力が報われる姿を
You know what to do, Sanada.
（金盛）頼んだぞ 真田
（真田）ああ
Yeah.
But I don't think it'll be easy.
そう簡単にはいかねえ …か
（アナウンス）副将戦
（小関）ンンッ…
Fourth bout.
On the west side, Ozeki-kun.
（アナウンス）西 小関君
On the east side, Sanada-kun.
東 真田君
Sada, sorry about this, but
I'm gonna end this team match here.
沙田(さだ)　お前には悪いが
俺で 団体戦の勝利 決めてくるぜ
It's no skin off my nose.
（沙田）別に 悪いも何も…
I figured we'd win in three bouts.
俺は てっきり 中堅戦までで
３勝してるもんだと思ってましたよ
I can't believe Gen-chan lost.
まさか源(げん)ちゃんが負けるなんて…
Lay off or you'll make me cry!
あんま言うな！　泣くぞ！
Don't take these guys lightly.
ヤツらをナメるんじゃねえ
真田　お前もだ
Sanada, that goes for you, too.
Kanamori, don't worry about me.
金盛　そんな心配は要らねえ
I take Ozeki more seriously
than anyone else here.
俺は ここにいる誰よりも
小関をナメてねえ
Push, push, Ishi High!
（生徒たち）
押せ押せ 石高！　押せ押せ…
Push, push, Ishi High!
Stay calm!
（桐仁）落ち着いていこう
（蛍）部長 ファイト〜！
Captain, fight!
Hands on the ground.
（審判）手をついて
（生徒たち）
押せ押せ 石高！　押せ押せ…
Hey!
Wait, we hadn't started yet!
（審判）待て！　まだだ！
A false start?
（男性１）立ち合い 不成立
He charged before Ozeki had
put his hands on the ground.
（男性２）
小関が手をつく前に 突っかけた！
お… 脅かさないでよ
もう終わったのかと思ったじゃない
D-Don't scare me like that!
I thought it was all over.
He did that on purpose, didn't he?
（蛍）今の わざとですよね？
（桐仁）ああ
Yeah.
All the focus he was building up
for his charge has dissipated.
せっかく立ち合いに高めた集中力が
完全に途切れた
And being dumped on his backside may
have replaced it with thoughts of losing.
それに
尻もちをつかされたことで—
負けのイメージを
植え付けられたかもしれない
That was dirty, Sanada!
（男性）ひでえぞ 真田！
（男性）ちゃんと立ち合えよ！
Face off fair and square!
Damn, Sanada-san's
ex-delinquent blood is raging.
やべえ　真田さんの元不良の血が
騒いじゃってんスね
I've heard tales of his exploits.
俺は知ってますよ 数々の武勇伝
He's no delinquent.
あいつは不良なんかじゃねえ
But I know why people might get that idea.
（金盛）だが そう言われる理由に
心当たりはあるがな
Hands on the ground.
（審判）手をついて
H-Hey... Is he ready?
お… おい　もう大丈夫なのか？
Captain, take a breath.
部長　ひと呼吸 置いて！
Spirit!
はっきよい！
He wasn't intimidated.
He seems even more focused!
萎縮するどころか
張り差してきた！
I was one step behind.
（真田）ひと足遅かったか
It seems you awakened in that moment.
どうやら お前は さっきの
あの瞬間に 目覚めちまったらしい
Even I'm surprised at how calm I am.
（小関）
自分でも驚くほど落ち着いてる
Ishi High's Sanada-san charged at me.
あの石高の真田さんが
突っかけてきた
He considers me an equal.
俺を対等に見てるんだ
Ushio, guys... I'm gonna win!
潮！　みんな！　俺 勝つよ！
He got the first hit in,
（真田）先手は取られたが—
but I'm not nice enough to
let him win just because of that!
そのまま負けてやるほど
俺も お人よしじゃあねえぜ
He knocked his hand away!
腰で上手(うわて)を切った！
Rats. He had a good hold!
くそ！　いい所持ったのに
Honestly, Sanada has the
better technique, but...
（桐仁）正直 技では
真田が一枚うわて　だが…
You can overcome that, Captain.
（桐仁）部長なら超えられる
心で技を凌駕(りょうが)しろ！
Overcome his skill with your heart!
What do you mean, he's not a delinquent?
（荒木）不良じゃないって
どういうことですか？
Sanada-san's famous for the
"Night of Blood Spray" incident!
真田さんといえば あの伝説の—
“血煙の一夜事件”で
有名じゃないスか
He defended the sumo club
against a hundred thugs!
押し寄せる100人の
ヤンキー相手に—
たったひとりで相撲部を守ったって
I heard it was thirty.
俺が聞いたのは
確か30人くらいって…
ちょ…　十分ヤバイっすよ
Wha... That's still plenty!
Enough of this nonsense.
（金盛）
くだらねえ話してんじゃねえよ
There's a bout going on.
（金盛）試合中だ
（荒木･間宮）ウ… ウッス
Y-Yes, sir.
And it really is nonsense.
本当に くだらねえ話だ
What do you mean,
you're quitting the sumo club?!
（金盛）相撲部 辞めるって
どういうつもりだよ！？
What's wrong, Kanamori? Are you angry?
（真田）
何だよ？　金盛　怒ってんの？
Ishigami
High
School
Sumo
Club
I thought you liked sumo.
（金盛）お前
相撲 好きじゃなかったのかよ？
I do. I love it more than anyone.
好きだよ
俺ほどの相撲好き そうはいねえさ
I've just got my hands full right now.
ただ 今ちょっと取り込み中でよ
訳は また今度 話すわ
I'll fill you in when I see you.
Where are you right now—
（金盛）お前 今どこ…
（電話を切る音）
Wh-What's your problem?!
（不良）な… 何なんだ？　お前
冗談だっつってんだろう！
We said it was a joke!
A joke?
（真田）冗談？
道場に火をつけようってのがか？
Setting fire to the dojo?
Don't mess with people
on the straight and narrow!
マジでやってるヤツらを
からかうんじゃねえよ！
What's all this?
（金盛）何なんだよ？　これは
You quit so the sumo club
wouldn't get into trouble for this?
退部したから
もう相撲部は関係ねえってか？
Taking all the blame on yourself...
１人で
泥をかぶるようなマネしやがって…
Wait, why's your fist...
（金盛）つうか なんで拳…
（真田）うん？　ああ
Oh, because it would've been
a waste to use sumo on this lot.
こんな連中に 相撲使うなんて
もったいねえだろう
Spouting nonsense is
what Sanada does best.
（金盛）くだらねえが 真田らしい
He loves sumo and the Ishi High
sumo club more than anyone!
そして 誰よりも相撲を…
石高相撲部を愛しているのは真田だ
His throat!
（蛍）喉輪(のどわ)！
（佑真）しっかり腰を落とせ！
Drop your weight!
His furious attacks aren't
giving him chance to breathe!
（男性１）
息をつかせぬ怒濤(どとう)の連続攻撃！
Sanada's being merciless against Ozeki!
（男性２）真田のヤツ
小関相手に容赦なしだぜ！
"Merciless"?
Even that isn't enough to beat him.
（真田）容赦？　こいつに勝つには
これでも足りねえくらいだ
You don't know the strength Ozeki possesses.
A strength completely unlike mine.
（真田）お前らは知らねえんだ
俺とは違う小関の持つ強さを
Man, I so wanna sumo again.
（真田）あ〜 相撲取りてえ
早く停学 明けねえかな
I hope this suspension ends soon.
（小関）ンンッ…
（男子生徒）なに？　あれ
What's he doing?
I heard he can't use the dojo
because the delinquents took it over.
（女子生徒）不良たちのせいで
道場が使えないらしいよ
Wow, that's one determined guy.
（男子生徒）うわ　よくやるな
So you've had trouble
with delinquents, too?
あいつも不良に悩まされるクチか
Well, I feel for you,
まあ 気の毒だとは思うが
but unlike you, I fought back
and drove the delinquents out.
俺は お前と違って
戦って 勝ち取ったぜ
At first, I thought he was just being vain
and figured he wouldn't keep it up for long.
（真田）最初は
“不幸な自分に酔っているだけ”
“それも長くは続かない”
そう思っていた
But the sympathy and disdain
I felt slowly changed to fear.
だが 最初に抱いた同情や軽蔑は
いつしか 恐怖に変わっていた
I pride myself on liking
sumo more than anyone.
誰よりも相撲が好きだという
自負があった
だが
もし俺が こいつと同じ状況に…
But if I was in his shoes...
Training by myself in
such an awful situation...
このおぞましい環境に
ひとり置かれたとき—
Could I keep at it for
two years without cracking?
こいつのように
２年もの間 折れずに…
Could I keep doing stomps and enjoy it?
楽しそうに しこを踏めるのか？
Have you even noticed how insane
your strength to endure is?
（真田）お前は気づいているのか？
その狂気じみた耐え抜く強さに
Sanada-san's attacks...
（間宮）真田さんの攻撃が…
（荒木）止まった
...have dried up.
It's really hard to fight the
captain when he's defending.
守りに入られると
ホントやりづれえんだ 部長は
Yeah.
Until now, the captain always
lacked patience in a bout.
今まで部長は 勝負を焦って—
He charged forward at the wrong times
and ended up losing.
不十分な形のまま 前に出て
負けていた
But now, he's learned to take his time,
dictate the pace, and then go for the kill.
だが 今の部長なら—
じっくりと自分の形を作ってから
確かな１歩を踏み出せる
Their moves are canceling each other out,
but that's only half the battle.
組み手は五分
がっぷり四つの引き付け合い
With their strength so evenly matched,
their hearts will be put to the test.
互いの実力が拮抗(きっこう)した今
試されるのは心
The one with the more heart will win.
気持ちで上回れた者の頭上に
軍配は上がる
Captain!
（蛍）部長！
（佑真）もうひと息だ！
Just a little more!
Sanada-san!
真田さん！
Frankly, that stuff about winning and being
the best in Japan doesn't feel real to me.
（小関）正直 優勝とか日本一とか
いまだにピンと来てないんだ
でも…
But...
We want to see you emerge triumphant
and have your hard work rewarded.
勝って その努力が報われる姿を
俺たちに見せてくれ
If they say that,
（小関）みんなが
そう言ってくれるなら—
I'll use every last ounce
of strength in my body!
最後の１滴まで 俺は振り絞れる！
Damn, this is bad.
（真田）くそ！　マズイ
前半の一方的な攻めで 息が…
My opening flurry has left me out of breath!
ブハッ！
（小関）今だ！
Now!
（小関）グ〜ッ！
（間宮）真田さん！
Sanada-san!
いけ 小関！　勝てー！
Push him out, Ozeki!
Win!
Am I going to lose?
（真田）負けるのか？　俺が
No, I like sumo more!
相撲が好きな気持ちは…
俺のほうが上だーっ！
（桐仁）あっ…
（蛍）部長ーっ！
Captain!
ンッ…　ど… どっち！？
Wh-Who won?!
（審判）西の勝ち！
West side wins!
（西郷）２勝２敗！
（舟木）決着は大将戦だ！
Two wins, two losses.
It's down to a decider!
Captain!
（蛍たち）部長〜！
（千比路）ハハッ！
You guys...
みんな…
It's too early for tears, captain.
（桐仁）泣くには まだ早いよ 部長
Yeah, it's not over yet.
（小関）ああ　まだ終わってない
Ushio, I want you to win.
潮　勝ってほしい！
It's now your turn to have
your hard work rewarded.
次は お前が報われる番だぞ
Here I go.
行ってくる
I finally get to fight you.
やっと 君と戦える
Good morning.
おはよう…　うん？
Hey! Who the hell are you?!
ちょっと！　あんた 誰よ？
そこは お兄ちゃんの席！
That's my brother's seat!
I need to eat and get bigger.
もっと食べて 大きくならねえとな
No!
（礼奈）イヤ〜ッ！
ハッ！
ハァハァ…　夢か…
Next Bout
"Demon and Moon"
It was a dream...